<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Home on SWIFT-HEP</title><link>/</link><description>Recent content in Home on SWIFT-HEP</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 20:02:52 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Intelligent data and workflow management</title><link>/workpackages/01_data_and_workflow/overview/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 14:34:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>/workpackages/01_data_and_workflow/overview/</guid><description>Summary Progress Meetings, mailing list and contacts Meetings Forum (SWIFT-HEP wide) Convenors: David Colling (Imperial, CMS), Alastair Dewhurst (RAL-SCD) [contact by email]</description></item><item><title>Event generators</title><link>/workpackages/02_event_generators/overview/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 14:34:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>/workpackages/02_event_generators/overview/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Simulation</title><link>/workpackages/03_simulation/overview/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 14:35:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>/workpackages/03_simulation/overview/</guid><description>Here we put a bit of progress on WP3 simulation</description></item><item><title>Reconstruction and trigger</title><link>/workpackages/04_reconstruction_and_trigger/overview/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 14:35:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>/workpackages/04_reconstruction_and_trigger/overview/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Analysis Systems</title><link>/workpackages/05_analysis/overview/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 19:47:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>/workpackages/05_analysis/overview/</guid><description>Summary The analysis systems workpackage focuses on two aspects of HEP data analysis: efficient iteration and portability of code.
Progress The analysis work package is due to start on the 1st of April 2022. We are currently in the planning and hiring phase.
Collaboration with other HEP efforts Planned collaboration with IRIS-HEP and HSF by contributing to the Analysis Grand Challenges.
Meetings, mailing list and contacts Meetings Forum (SWIFT-HEP wide) Convenors: Luke Kreczko (CMS/LZ), Eduardo Rodrigues (LHCb) [contact by email]</description></item><item><title>Training</title><link>/workpackages/training/overview/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 14:35:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>/workpackages/training/overview/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Organisation</title><link>/organisation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 11:53:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>/organisation/</guid><description> Management The SWIFT-HEP coordinator is Davide Costanzo (Sheffield) and deputy Conor Fitzpatrick (Manchester). The current conveners of the work packages are: WP1: David Colling (Imperial, CMS) and Alastair Dewhurst (RAL-SCD, Tier0) WP2: Andy Buckley (Glasgow, ATLAS) and Marek Schoenherr (Durham, Theory) WP3: Adam Davis (Manchester, LHCb) and Ben Morgan (Warwick, DUNE, LEGEND) WP4: Chris Jones (Cambridge, LHCb) and Stewart Martin-Haugh (RAL-PPD, ATLAS) WP5: Luke Kreczko (Bristol, LZ) and Eduardo Rodrigues (Liverpool, LHCb) Advisory board The advisory board is formed by the UK spokespersons of the major experiments as well as the PI of GridPP and IRIS ATLAS: Sinead Farrington CMS: Claire Shepherd-Themistocleous (Chair) LHCb: DUNE: GridPP: IRIS: Jon Hays Current team People currently funded to work on SWIFT-HEP are</description></item><item><title>The simulation Opticks team to participate in the UK Hackathon 2022</title><link>/posts/2022-02-01-gpuhackathon/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 10:42:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2022-02-01-gpuhackathon/</guid><description>What is the name of your code/application: Opticks Application details: Optical photon propagation from Cherenkov processes is one of the most time consuming processes of all LHCb simulation. As the problem is embarrasingly parallel and explicitly needed by many particle physics experiments around the world, much work has been undertaken to exploit the RTX cores of modern NVIDIA GPUs to accelerate optical photon simulation and speaking directly to OptiX from the core Geant4 implementation of the detector geometry.</description></item><item><title>Overview</title><link>/overview/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 20:43:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>/overview/</guid><description>Science and strategy Computing contributes significantly to the cost of operating HEP experiments, with the UK currently providing about 13.5% of the total ATLAS computing resources, 6% for CMS, 20% for LHCb and a significant fraction expected for DUNE. Resources are provided as a cross-experiment initiative via GridPP with a cost of about £5M/year. The overall resource requirement is expected to increase in the coming years as the experiment upgrades are designed to increase the overall data throughput by a factor of 10.</description></item><item><title>SWIFT-HEP workshop on 23-24 March 2022</title><link>/posts/2021-12-03-third-workshop/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 12:02:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2021-12-03-third-workshop/</guid><description>The third SWIFT-HEP workshop will be held in Durham on 23-24 March.
The workshop is co-located with the GridPP47 meeting, a joint session is planned as well as common social activities. A dedicated SWIFT-HEP workshop will be held over 1.5 days.</description></item><item><title>SWIFT-HEP workshop on 2-3 November 2021</title><link>/posts/2021-11-02-second-workshop/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 11:02:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>/posts/2021-11-02-second-workshop/</guid><description>The second SWIFT-HEP workshop was held in person at Imperial College on 2-3 November.
The meeting agenda is in Indico.</description></item><item><title>SWIFT-HEP starts!</title><link>/posts/2021-04-01-start-of-swifthep/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 11:02:41 +0100</pubDate><guid>/posts/2021-04-01-start-of-swifthep/</guid><description>SWIFT-HEP started on 1 April 2021 as a new project to provide software for HEP experiments.
STFC press release.</description></item></channel></rss>