<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on SWIFT-HEP</title><link>https://swift-hep.github.io/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on SWIFT-HEP</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2022 12:33:21 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://swift-hep.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>New job opportunity in SWIFT-HEP (analysis) - deadline 14th Sep 2022</title><link>https://swift-hep.github.io/posts/2022-08-19-wp5-job-advert/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2022 12:33:21 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://swift-hep.github.io/posts/2022-08-19-wp5-job-advert/</guid><description>We are pleased to announce two new job openings at the University of Bristol. Both openings are within the particle physics group and will be constructed by two of the four areas below:
Development of efficient and fast software for particle physics in the context of the SWIFT-HEP initiative (with a focus on Python). Software development on highly parallel computing architectures for LHCb-upgrade II, with a focus on Graphcore’s novel IPU processors (C++ -based).</description></item><item><title>The simulation Opticks team to participate in the UK Hackathon 2022</title><link>https://swift-hep.github.io/posts/2022-02-01-gpuhackathon/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 10:42:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://swift-hep.github.io/posts/2022-02-01-gpuhackathon/</guid><description>What is the name of your code/application: Opticks Application details: Optical photon propagation from Cherenkov processes is one of the most time consuming processes of all LHCb simulation. As the problem is embarrasingly parallel and explicitly needed by many particle physics experiments around the world, much work has been undertaken to exploit the RTX cores of modern NVIDIA GPUs to accelerate optical photon simulation and speaking directly to OptiX from the core Geant4 implementation of the detector geometry.</description></item><item><title>SWIFT-HEP workshop on 23-24 March 2022</title><link>https://swift-hep.github.io/posts/2021-12-03-third-workshop/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 12:02:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://swift-hep.github.io/posts/2021-12-03-third-workshop/</guid><description>The third SWIFT-HEP workshop will be held in Durham on 23-24 March.
The workshop is co-located with the GridPP47 meeting, a joint session is planned as well as common social activities. A dedicated SWIFT-HEP workshop will be held over 1.5 days.</description></item><item><title>SWIFT-HEP workshop on 2-3 November 2021</title><link>https://swift-hep.github.io/posts/2021-11-02-second-workshop/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 11:02:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://swift-hep.github.io/posts/2021-11-02-second-workshop/</guid><description>The second SWIFT-HEP workshop was held in person at Imperial College on 2-3 November.
The meeting agenda is in Indico.</description></item><item><title>SWIFT-HEP starts!</title><link>https://swift-hep.github.io/posts/2021-04-01-start-of-swifthep/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 11:02:41 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://swift-hep.github.io/posts/2021-04-01-start-of-swifthep/</guid><description>SWIFT-HEP started on 1 April 2021 as a new project to provide software for HEP experiments.
STFC press release.</description></item></channel></rss>